[
  {
    "name": "Declaration and commenting",
    "id": "1001",
    "questions": [
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "How to declare a variable to hold an integer value?",
        "choices": [
          "var a=0",
          "int a=0",
          "a=0",
          "num a=0"
        ],
        "answer": "a=0"
      },
      {
        "type": "blank",
        "question": "How to comment a single line?",
        "answer": "#"
      },
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "Which is one of the way to declare a string constant?",
        "choices": [
          "char foo[] = \"foo\"",
          "String foo = \"foo\"",
          "foo=\"foo\"",
          "char foo=\"foo\""
        ],
        "answer": "foo=\"foo\""
      },
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "If NAME is the variable, which is one of the way to print its contents?",
        "choices": [
          "NAME",
          "$NAME",
          "(NAME)",
          "*(NAME)"
        ],
        "answer": "$NAME"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "name": "Operators",
    "id": "1002",
    "questions": [
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "Which is conditional OR operator?",
        "choices": [
          "or",
          "|",
          "||",
          "$or"
        ],
        "answer": "||"
      },
      {
        "type": "blank",
        "question": "___ is conditional AND operator in Bash?",
        "answer": "&&"
      },
      {
        "type": "blank",
        "question": "___ is the operator to test two integers are not algebraically equal?",
        "answer": "-ne"
      },
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "___ symbol is used to append output of a command to a file",
        "choices": [
          "No such operator",
          ">",
          ">>",
          "|"
        ],
        "answer": ">>"
      },
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "___ symbol is used to start a process in the background",
        "choices": [
          "%",
          ">",
          ">>",
          "&"
        ],
        "answer": "&"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "name": "Conditions and Loops",
    "id": "1003",
    "questions": [
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "Which is basic conditional branching statement in Bash?",
        "choices": [
          "check",
          "is",
          "if",
          "yes"
        ],
        "answer": "if"
      },
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "Which is one of the syntax for FOR loop?",
        "choices": [
          "for (( variable initialization; condition; variable update ))",
          "for (( condition; variable update ; exit status))",
          "for ((condition 1; condition 2; condition 3))",
          "for (( variable increment ; variable decrement; condition ))"
        ],
        "answer": "for (( variable initialization; condition; variable update ))"
      },
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "for ((a=1; a=3; a++)); do <statement>; done; How many times will the statement inside the loop get executed?",
        "choices": [
          "5",
          "1",
          "6",
          "infinite"
        ],
        "answer": "infinite"
      },
      {
        "type": "blank",
        "question": "What is the statement used to jump out of a loop",
        "answer": "break"
      },
      {
        "type": "blank",
        "question": "Say true or false.  Statements in *) will be executed in case statement when none of the other pattern matches.",
        "answer": "true"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "name": "Functions",
    "id": "1004",
    "questions": [
      {
        "type": "blank",
        "question": "What is the command to get input from the user",
        "answer": "read"
      },
      {
        "type": "blank",
        "question": "If NAME is the variable, how to get only its first 7 characters in Bash?",
        "answer": "${NAME:0:7}"
      },
      {
        "type": "blank",
        "question": "If NAME is the variable, how to create a new string replacing all occurence of \"a\" with \"o\" in Bash  ?",
        "answer": "${VARIABLE/a/o}"
      },
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "Which is one of the syntax for function declaration?",
        "choices": [
          "<return type> <function name>(<args>)",
          "<args> <function name>(<return type>)",
          "def <function name> (<args>)",
          "function <function name> ()"
        ],
        "answer": "function <function name> ()"
      },
      {
        "type": "choice",
        "question": "If foo is the function, how to call foo with 1 as argument?",
        "choices": [
          "foo 1",
          "foo(1)",
          "foo(&1)",
          "call foo 1"
        ],
        "answer": "foo 1"
      }
    ]
  }
]